desimartini.com 2019-05-15

# Privacy Policy - Desimartini

**PRIVACY POLICY**

HT Digital Streams Limited (hereinafter referred as “HTDSL”) recognizes the importance of maintaining the privacy of every user who visits our website. We value your privacy and appreciate your trust in us. We are committed to be transparent about the data we collect about you, how it is used and with whom it is shared. 

This Privacy Policy applies when you use/visit our website, mobile or tablet application, or any other online service (collectively, the “Services”) that links or refers to it. It does not governs or apply to information collected or used by HTDSL or its group companies through any other means. 

By visiting and/or using our website, you agree to this Privacy Policy. We strongly recommend you to read this privacy policy so that you understand our approach towards the use of your personal data. 

HTDSL is a subsidiary of HT Media Ltd. It is licensed to operate and manage the websites of HT Media Ltd. and its subsidiaries (hereinafter referred as “Company”) . HTDSL manages [hindustantimes.com](https://www.hindustantimes.com/), [livehindustan.com](https://www.livehindustan.com/), [desimartini.com](https://www.desimartini.com/) and [livemint.com](https://www.livemint.com/). 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time as in required. 

INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

We collect information directly from user(s) , from third-parties and automatically through our websites/mobile applications. Registration for the Services may require that you supply certain personal information such as name, age, sex, contact number, email address and demographic information (area, location, IP address etc) to register. To aid convenience, users can sign up on any of our sites, and we extend the same login credentials to sign in to any of the other sites. (Single Sign-on feature). You may also register or link your account through third party accounts such as Facebook, Google etc. 

We collect limited information about your computer's connection to the Internet, including your IP address, when you visit our site. Your IP address does not identify you personally. We also collect and may store information that your computer or mobile device provides to us in connection with your use of our website/apps such as your browser type, type of computer or mobile device, browser language, IP address, mobile carrier, unique device identifier, location, and requested and referring URLs. We also receive information when you view content on or otherwise interact with our website/app/services, even if you have not created an account. We use this information to deliver our web pages to you upon request, to tailor our site to the interests of our users, to measure traffic on the website. This information may also be used by our advertisers/third party companies to personalize content, ads etc. 

HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION 

  * We collect information directly from you when you register with us. 
  * We collect information (whether you are registered or not registered with us) when you browse our sites/apps, open or respond to an email from us (promotional or informational), 
  * When you post a comment on our website or raise a query/question to us through phone or email. 
  * We collect information from you when you register with us by linking your social media or third party accounts. By doing this, you are authorizing them to share with us certain information from such accounts, and authorizing us to collect, store, and use this in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 
  * We collect information from you using third party tools, browser cookies and web beacons in order to improve user experience. 
  * Device Information We may collect non-personal information about the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access the service, such as IP address, geo-location information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language and other information for the purpose of providing customized information on the browser. 
  * Location Information  Our mobile application and websites may capture your current location if you choose to enable GPS feature in the app or browser. 

COOKIE POLICY , PIXELS AND TRACKING 

Cookies are small text files which contain a small amount of information that is downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, or visit partner website which recognises that cookie, your device is able to communicate with our website and the website can read the information held in that cookie. 

We use Cookies to help you efficiently browse our websites and to save you time by not having to re-enter your details/preferences each time you visit. Cookies allow us to provide you with information and show you content relevant to you. We also use Cookies to analyse how our customers interact with our websites so we can improve the customer journey. 

You can choose to accept or decline cookies in your browser settings. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to reject cookies if you prefer. You may find more help about managing cookies in your browser: [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en), [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-in/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies), [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences) & [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US). This may prevent you from having complete website experience by affecting the access to some of the links, services or features. Information collected by cookies and web beacons is not personally identifiable. 

HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION 

  * To Provide and Manage the Services You Request. This includes, for example, processing your subscription, sending you electronic newsletters, or enabling you to participate in the features provided by the Services. It also includes providing personalized content and recommendations to you, including by email. Through such features, we are able to bring you information and content tailored to your individual interests and needs. 
  * To Reach You: We may periodically contact you with offers and information about the Services and our affiliates, including in connection with your accounts, online surveys, legal notices, news stories, new features that you are entitled to access, and other important information. You may opt out of receiving commercial email messages from us by following the instructions contained in those email messages. 
  * To Customise Advertising. We may use your information to facilitate the delivery of targeted ads, promotions, and offers to you, on behalf of ourselves and advertisers, on and off the Services. 
  * Understand Our Readers and Users. The Services conduct research on our users’ demographics, interests and behavior based on the information we collect. We do this to better understand and serve our users, and to improve our products and services. 
  * To Protect the Rights of the Services and others. We may use your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, its employees or agents, or other users and to comply with applicable law. 
  * Consent. We may otherwise use your information with your consent or at your direction. HOW WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION The following provides information about entities with which we may share information. Our practices vary depending on the type of information. 
  * Logging In Through Social Media Services: If you log into the Services with a social media service or if you connect a social media account with the Services, we may share your information with that social media service. The social media services’ use of the shared information will be governed by the social media services’ privacy policy and your social media account settings. If you do not want your information shared in this way, do not connect your social media service account with your Services. 
  * Business Partners: We may also share your information with business partners to provide you with services that you request. 
  * Service Providers: We may share information with vendors providing contractual services to us, such as hosting vendors, advertising service providers, and list managers. We also may share your information, including your payment information, as appropriate to process your payments for the Services or complete a transaction. 
  * Other Parties When Required by Law or As Necessary to Protect Our Users and Services: We may share your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, our employees or agents or users or to comply with applicable law or legal process, including responding to requests from public and government authorities. 
  * Affiliates : We may share information within our family of affiliated companies and business associates. 
  * Third Parties that Provide Content, Advertising, or Functionality : When you use our Services, third parties may collect or receive certain information about you and/or your use of the Services (e.g., hashed data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, information about your interactions with advertisements and other content), including through the use of cookies, beacons, mobile ad identifiers, and similar technologies, in order to provide content, advertising, or functionality or to measure and analyze ad performance, on our Services or other websites or platforms. This information may be combined with information collected across different websites, online services, and other linked or associated devices. These third parties may use your information to improve their own services and consistent with their own privacy policies. 
  * Other Parties in Connection With a Corporate Transaction : We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event that we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party, such as in the event of a merger, acquisition, or in connection with a bankruptcy reorganization. 
  * Otherwise With Your Consent or At Your Direction :  In addition to the sharing described in this Privacy Policy, we may share information about you with third parties whenever you consent to or direct such sharing. 
  * We also may share other information with third parties in a manner that does not identify particular users, including, for example, aggregated data about how users are using our Services. 
  * Links to Third-Party Sites : Our Services may link to third-party websites and services that are outside our control. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by other websites or other services. You should exercise caution, and review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use. 

ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION 

You may access or modify your personal information by signing on to the website. We will not modify the information provided by you. However, you must update your personal information as soon as such changes are necessitated. Upon your request, we will close your account and remove your personal information from view as soon as reasonably possible, based on your account activity and in accordance with applicable law(s). However, we will retain the required personal information from closed accounts to comply with law, Avoid/check illegal and/or potentially prohibited activities and to enforce User Agreements; Comply with any court judgment / decree / order / directive / legal & government authority /applicable law; Investigate potential violations or applicable national & international laws; Investigate deliberate damage to the website/services or its legitimate operation; Detect, prevent, or otherwise address security and/or technical issues; safeguard p the rights, property or safety of company and/or its Directors, employees and the general public at large; Respond to Claims of third parties; and take such other actions as may be permitted by law 

SHOULD YOU WANT TO OPT OUT

If we possess your contact information, we may want to keep you posted about our products, services and events, through email. Should you prefer not to keep up to date with company related news and latest information on services and receive such marketing materials, please click on the unsubscribe link in the communication that you recieve. 

Further, a user may withdraw the consent given to the company on the website by communicating the same to us in writing on the email provided in the contact us section of the website or by clicking here. However, such withholding of information or withdrawal of consent may result in company not being able to provide services and facilities. 

We will update your preferences as soon as reasonably practical. However, do note, if you opt out of the companies emailing list, as described here, we will not be able to remove your personal information from the databases of affiliates, franchisees or business partners with which we have already shared your personal information, prior to the date of your opt-out request. 

**REACH OUT TO US ******

 ** **For any complaint related to our services or content of the website the aggrieved person may raise the query/complaint within a period of 7 (seven) days from the date of first publication to the email id mentioned herein:****

 ** **Email:  privacymanager@hindustantimes.com ****

****___________  
HT Digital Streams Ltd.  
Corporate Office: 2nd Floor 18-20 KG Marg   
New Delhi-110001  
Phone: + 91 11 66561123 ****
